<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211;  </title>
	<atom:link href="/archives/category/uncategorized/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 09:42:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/gmail.fw_-150x150.png</url>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211;  </title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Strengthening Economic Ties: Shenzhen Global Investment Conference in Milan Attracts Prominent Figures</title>
		<link>/archives/323</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 09:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://grosso.link/?p=323</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a significant move to foster Sino-Italian economic relations, Counselor Geng Xiewei graced the Shenzhen Global Investment Conference&#8217;s Italian segment in Milan on November 28, delivering a keynote speech that highlighted the deep-rooted cooperation between China and Italy. The event, notable for its gathering of over a hundred attendees from various government sectors and the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a significant move to foster Sino-Italian economic relations, Counselor Geng Xiewei graced the Shenzhen Global Investment Conference&#8217;s Italian segment in Milan on November 28, delivering a keynote speech that highlighted the deep-rooted cooperation between China and Italy.</p>
<p>The event, notable for its gathering of over a hundred attendees from various government sectors and the business community, featured key personalities such as Sun Xiaoyu, Chief Representative of the Shenzhen European Economic and Trade Office, and Dominotti, Secretary-General of the Italian Foreign Trade Association.</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="wp-image-326 alignleft" src="http://localhost/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/11.jpg" alt="" width="315" height="472" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/11.jpg 580w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/12/11-200x300.jpg 200w" sizes="(max-width: 315px) 100vw, 315px" /></p>
<p>Counselor Geng emphasized the comprehensive strategic partnership between China and Italy, underscoring the substantial foundation for collaboration that exists between the two nations. He highlighted Shenzhen&#8217;s significant achievements as China&#8217;s first Special Economic Zone and a central city in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area, particularly in terms of high-level international economic openness. Geng expressed optimism about the expansive opportunities for cooperation, urging businesses from both countries to fully leverage various preferential policies, maintain close communication and cooperation, and collectively contribute to the development of Shenzhen and the deepening of Sino-Italian economic and trade cooperation.</p>
<p>The event also saw the presence of Deputy Consul Li Siwei from the Consulate&#8217;s Economic and Commercial Office, further reinforcing the importance of the conference in strengthening Sino-Italian economic ties.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Délégation de Shenzhen en Suisse : Une Alliance Innovante s&#8217;Esquisse à Lausanne</title>
		<link>/archives/309</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 08:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://grosso.link/?p=309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lausanne, Suisse &#8211; 25 septembre 2023 &#8211; Une délégation de la ville chinoise de Shenzhen, célèbre pour son innovation technologique, a atterri hier dans la cité technophile de Lausanne, en Suisse, pour un sommet économique et commercial historique. La rencontre, qui a eu lieu au Parc d&#8217;Innovation de l&#8217;École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL), a été [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="ember1261" class="ember-view reader-content-blocks__paragraph"><strong>Lausanne, Suisse &#8211; 25 septembre 2023</strong> &#8211; Une délégation de la ville chinoise de Shenzhen, célèbre pour son innovation technologique, a atterri hier dans la cité technophile de Lausanne, en Suisse, pour un sommet économique et commercial historique. La rencontre, qui a eu lieu au Parc d&#8217;Innovation de l&#8217;École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL), a été honorée par la présence de Wang Qiang, membre permanent du Comité municipal de Shenzhen.</p>
<div class="reader-image-block reader-image-block--resize">
<figure class="reader-image-block__figure">
<div class="ivm-image-view-model   ">
<div class="ivm-view-attr__img-wrapper display-flex"><img decoding="async" id="ember1262" class="ivm-view-attr__img--centered  reader-image-block__img evi-image lazy-image ember-view" src="https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/D4E12AQHQB12Kfg0Tzg/article-inline_image-shrink_1500_2232/0/1695718509147?e=1701302400&amp;v=beta&amp;t=c5pcSzyFobgf_JqvdbRQiwwbFb17FZ8Qc90ix2wOUMo" alt="" /></div>
</div>
</figure>
</div>
<h3 id="ember1264" class="ember-view">Un Carrefour d&#8217;Esprits Innovants</h3>
<p id="ember1265" class="ember-view reader-content-blocks__paragraph">La Suisse domine les indices mondiaux d&#8217;innovation depuis douze ans, grâce notamment à ses avancées dans l&#8217;industrie moderne et les secteurs de haute technologie. La convergence de ces atouts suisses avec la réputation de Shenzhen en tant que foyer d&#8217;ingéniosité technologique soulève des questions intrigantes : quel genre de magie synergétique pourrait surgir de cet échange Est-Ouest ?</p>
<h3 id="ember1266" class="ember-view">Relier les Paysages Économiques</h3>
<p id="ember1267" class="ember-view reader-content-blocks__paragraph">Selon des sources au Bureau des Affaires Chinoises d&#8217;Outre-Mer de Shenzhen, des vidéos promotionnelles de Shenzhen et de son district de Nanshan ont été projetées pendant l&#8217;événement. Des représentants ont souligné les dernières opportunités et caractéristiques industrielles de Shenzhen. Le forum a également inclus des experts et chercheurs suisses qui ont exposé l&#8217;écosystème suisse de la recherche et de l&#8217;innovation.</p>
<h3 id="ember1268" class="ember-view">Commentaire Approfondi</h3>
<p id="ember1269" class="ember-view reader-content-blocks__paragraph">Il est particulièrement pertinent de noter que cet échange se déroule à Lausanne, une ville située dans la région francophone de la Suisse. La Suisse romande est un moteur de l&#8217;innovation dans le pays, en particulier dans les domaines de la biotechnologie et de l&#8217;éducation. Ce partenariat potentiel entre Shenzhen et Lausanne pourrait donc être une occasion en or pour stimuler non seulement les échanges commerciaux, mais aussi le partage de connaissances et d&#8217;expertise dans ces secteurs clés.</p>
<h3 id="ember1270" class="ember-view">Un Accent sur l&#8217;Investissement Mutuel</h3>
<p id="ember1271" class="ember-view reader-content-blocks__paragraph">La délégation de Shenzhen a engagé des discussions de projets avec plusieurs entreprises technologiques suisses en phase de démarrage, mettant particulièrement l&#8217;accent sur les environnements et les opportunités d&#8217;investissement. Les participants ont loué les infrastructures supérieures et les climats d&#8217;affaires favorables tant à Shenzhen qu&#8217;à la Grande Baie.</p>
<h3 id="ember1272" class="ember-view">Bâtir sur des Années de Partenariat</h3>
<p id="ember1273" class="ember-view reader-content-blocks__paragraph">La relation entre Shenzhen et la Suisse s&#8217;est rapprochée de plus en plus au fil des années. L&#8217;expertise de la Suisse dans des secteurs tels que le commerce, les services financiers, la biomédecine et la fabrication de précision s&#8217;aligne bien avec les stratégies de Shenzhen pour une relation symbiotique entre la fabrication avancée et les services modernes.</p>
<h3 id="ember1274" class="ember-view">Visite Pré-Sommet au Biopole</h3>
<p id="ember1275" class="ember-view reader-content-blocks__paragraph">Avant le sommet, la délégation de Shenzhen a visité le Biopole de Lausanne, le plus grand incubateur de biomédecine en Suisse, jetant les bases de futures collaborations dans le secteur biopharmaceutique. Les représentants d&#8217;entreprises des deux villes ont exprimé leur optimisme pour une coopération accrue à l&#8217;avenir.</p>
<div class="reader-image-block reader-image-block--resize">
<figure class="reader-image-block__figure">
<div class="ivm-image-view-model   ">
<div class="ivm-view-attr__img-wrapper display-flex"><img decoding="async" id="ember1276" class="ivm-view-attr__img--centered  reader-image-block__img evi-image lazy-image ember-view" src="https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/D4E12AQEiPMNFEKB5yw/article-inline_image-shrink_1500_2232/0/1695718519419?e=1701302400&amp;v=beta&amp;t=g6najXUV4f0XpLxwloprGqdZsM5nfPJj2AWrwJBrIIk" alt="" /></div>
</div>
</figure>
</div>
<p id="ember1279" class="ember-view reader-content-blocks__paragraph">En résumé, le sommet économique a servi de terreau fertile pour cultiver un nouveau chapitre dans les relations sino-suisses, favorisant un engagement mutuel envers un développement gagnant-gagnant et un leadership innovant.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>China&#8217;s Drive Towards Sensor Industry Dominance: A Deep Dive into its Implications</title>
		<link>/archives/288</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://grosso.link/?p=288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In recent years, China&#8217;s relentless pursuit of technological advancement has led to remarkable developments in various industries. One such domain is the sensor industry, where the country is making significant strides in strengthening its supply chain and fostering domestic champions. However, this progress has not escaped the watchful eyes of international observers, especially from the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In recent years, China&#8217;s relentless pursuit of technological advancement has led to remarkable developments in various industries. One such domain is the sensor industry, where the country is making significant strides in strengthening its supply chain and fostering domestic champions. However, this progress has not escaped the watchful eyes of international observers, especially from the United States and Europe.</p>
<p>China&#8217;s Determined Efforts to Strengthen Sensor Industry</p>
<p>China&#8217;s focus on &#8220;filling the gaps,&#8221; &#8220;solidifying the chain,&#8221; and &#8220;strengthening the chain&#8221; within the sensor industry has drawn praise from experts worldwide. By investing in specialized design software and production technology, they have aimed to enhance the overall sophistication of their sensor industry. Notably, the integration of MEMS technology with IC technology has brought about a modernized approach to sensor manufacturing, allowing China to compete at a global level.</p>
<p>Critics from the West, however, view China&#8217;s aggressive expansion in the sensor sector with cautious eyes. They argue that this strategic push might grant China an edge in the international market, potentially posing a challenge to established American and European sensor manufacturers. Concerns about intellectual property rights and fair competition arise, prompting Western nations to contemplate their response to this growing competition.</p>
<p>Nurturing Chinese Sensor Pioneers and Attracting Talent</p>
<p>China&#8217;s emphasis on creating a breeding ground for pioneering sensor companies has sparked admiration and concerns alike. By fostering a nurturing environment for indigenous sensor technology, the country seeks to close the gap between its products and those of leading Western competitors. The establishment of specialized centers like the &#8220;Intelligent Sensor Innovation Center&#8221; demonstrates China&#8217;s determination to develop cutting-edge technology.</p>
<p>From a Western perspective, there is a strong interest in understanding how these efforts will impact the global sensor market. Some experts argue that the rise of Chinese sensor companies could lead to a more diversified market with increased innovation and technological breakthroughs. At the same time, others fear that this development could disrupt Western manufacturers&#8217; market share and potentially lead to a shift in global dynamics.</p>
<p>Addressing the &#8220;Component Deficit&#8221; and Collaborative Solutions</p>
<p>The issue of China&#8217;s reliance on foreign imports for crucial sensor components remains a contentious topic. While China has made significant strides in various aspects of sensor manufacturing, the dependence on foreign suppliers for core components raises questions about the country&#8217;s long-term sustainability and self-reliance.</p>
<p>China&#8217;s determination to address the &#8220;component deficit&#8221; by mobilizing resources and collaborating with key stakeholders has garnered international attention. The notion of &#8220;cooperative technology breakthroughs&#8221; that transcends industry and professional boundaries has earned praise for its innovation-centric approach.</p>
<p>However, some skeptics view this effort as a potential avenue for forced technology transfer and intellectual property infringement. They caution Western businesses and governments to be vigilant and assertive in safeguarding their technological know-how.</p>
<p>Conclusion</p>
<p>China&#8217;s rapid ascent in the sensor industry represents a testament to its ambitions of becoming a technological superpower. The nation&#8217;s strategic focus on strengthening the sensor industry supply chain, nurturing local pioneers, and resolving the &#8220;component deficit&#8221; has garnered both admiration and skepticism from international observers.</p>
<p>As the global sensor landscape evolves, it is evident that China&#8217;s advancements will significantly influence the dynamics of the industry. How this will play out in the coming years will likely be a critical focal point for analysts, policymakers, and businesses worldwide. For now, all eyes are on the progress of China&#8217;s sensor industry and its implications on the global stage.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
