<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News &#8211;  </title>
	<atom:link href="/archives/category/news/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 07:03:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/gmail.fw_-150x150.png</url>
	<title>News &#8211;  </title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The &#8216;Superheroes&#8217; of the Chip Sector: The Rise of Product Managers</title>
		<link>/archives/330</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 07:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://grosso.link/?p=330</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When you think of product managers, you might envision young, fashion-forward individuals, Starbucks in hand, with a keen glint in their eye. Indeed, these are the magicians transforming startups from wandering lambs into guiding lions. This holds true even in the semiconductor industry. Product Managers Reflecting on the evolution of China&#8217;s chip sector, we&#8217;ve transitioned [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you think of product managers, you might envision young, fashion-forward individuals, Starbucks in hand, with a keen glint in their eye. Indeed, these are the magicians transforming startups from wandering lambs into guiding lions. This holds true even in the semiconductor industry.</p>
<p>Product Managers</p>
<p>Reflecting on the evolution of China&#8217;s chip sector, we&#8217;ve transitioned from Huawei Hisilicon&#8217;s &#8220;dynasty phase&#8221; to Unisoc&#8217;s &#8220;tech phase,&#8221; and now, we&#8217;re navigating the &#8220;product-focused&#8221; new era. Here, product managers serve as the team&#8217;s strategists, marrying technical know-how with market acumen &#8211; they&#8217;re practically walking encyclopedias.</p>
<p>Imagine the old chip companies like Mr. Wang lost on the street, glancing around aimlessly, unsure of which way to go. Enter the product manager, and suddenly Mr. Wang has GPS – not only does he know his direction, but he also knows where to find the best street food along the way, delightful!</p>
<p>But here&#8217;s the dilemma: where does one find such versatile product managers? Indeed, they are as rare as pandas in the wild. Especially in startup chip companies, you might be hoping for Iron Man but end up with a cockroach in armor.</p>
<p>In reality, often founders themselves have to step into the role of super product managers. They&#8217;re not just running the market but are deeply diving into customer needs, to the point where even their dreams are filled with product positioning. There’s a founder who recently turned &#8220;watching TV&#8221; into &#8220;market research,&#8221; claiming to decipher chip development trends from a debate show – talk about unique!</p>
<p>However, the truth remains: a successful chip company cannot flourish without a stellar product manager. Looking at our domestic chip design firms, those that are thriving invariably have that one pivotal figure, guiding the company with their wisdom and sweat.</p>
<p>So, while the journey of product managers in startups is fraught with challenges, perseverance pays off. As the company grows and resources increase, today&#8217;s &#8220;cockroaches&#8221; can transform into genuine &#8220;superheroes,&#8221; soaring freely.</p>
<p>Spring is coming to the chip sector, but for the flowers to bloom beautifully, it takes the silent, relentless efforts of our product managers. So, the next time you encounter a product manager, don’t forget to give them a thumbs up, because you might be looking at a future industry pioneer!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shenzhen-European Collaboration Blossoms in Biotech: A Glimpse into the Future of Health</title>
		<link>/archives/315</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 08:07:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://grosso.link/?p=315</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shenzhen, Nov.1, 2023 &#8211; In a remarkable display of international cooperation, the Shenzhen-European Economic and Trade Representative Office recently took  stage at the &#8220;Transnational Innovation in Biotech: Shenzhen-Italy Healthcare Special&#8221; event. This conference, held in the heart of Shenzhen, underscores the burgeoning collaboration between Shenzhen and Italy in the field of biotechnology and healthcare. Shenzhen, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shenzhen, Nov.1, 2023 &#8211; In a remarkable display of international cooperation, the Shenzhen-European Economic and Trade Representative Office recently took  stage at the &#8220;Transnational Innovation in Biotech: Shenzhen-Italy Healthcare Special&#8221; event. This conference, held in the heart of Shenzhen, underscores the burgeoning collaboration between Shenzhen and Italy in the field of biotechnology and healthcare.</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-385" src="http://localhost/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/2_7734664-1024x683-1.jpg" width="1024" height="683" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/2_7734664-1024x683-1.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2025/01/2_7734664-1024x683-1-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2025/01/2_7734664-1024x683-1-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>Shenzhen, known as the Silicon Valley of China, is no stranger to technological innovation. Its rapid development has made it a key player in various industries, including biotechnology. Meanwhile, Italy boasts a rich history of scientific achievement and is renowned for its contributions to the global healthcare landscape. Together, these regions represent a powerhouse of potential for advancements in biomedicine.</p>
<p>The event, featured a prominent address by Ms. Sun Xiaoyu, the Chief Representative of the Shenzhen-European Economic and Trade Representative Office. Her speech emphasized the critical role that Shenzhen plays in the global biotech arena and the willingness to explore innovative opportunities in cooperation with Italy. Ms. Sun stated, &#8220;Shenzhen has been at the forefront of driving innovation in biotechnology and healthcare. We eagerly welcome closer ties with our Italian counterparts to jointly advance medical technology and the healthcare sector. Through cross-border collaboration, we believe we can collectively shape a healthier and more prosperous future.&#8221;</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-386" src="http://localhost/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/2_6872445-1024x683-1.jpg" width="1024" height="683" alt="" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/2_6872445-1024x683-1.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2025/01/2_6872445-1024x683-1-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2025/01/2_6872445-1024x683-1-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>The conference attracted a diverse group of experts, entrepreneurs, and government representatives from across Europe and China. Discussions revolved around the latest trends, challenges, and opportunities in the fields of biomedicine, health tech, and medical research. Participants shared invaluable experiences and insights related to medical technology, clinical research, and pharmaceutical development.</p>
<p>The collaboration between Shenzhen and Italy holds great promise. Both regions possess robust research resources and innovation capabilities. This synergy paves the way for remarkable breakthroughs in biotechnology and healthcare, with the potential to positively impact the lives of millions worldwide.</p>
<p>By actively participating in this international science and innovation exchange, the Shenzhen-European Economic and Trade Representative Office has provided a vital platform for deepening cooperation between Shenzhen and its European partners. Shenzhen remains committed to strengthening its global connections and fostering technological innovation, contributing significantly to the growth of the biomedicine and healthcare sectors. This event showcases the pivotal role of the Shenzhen-European Economic and Trade Representative Office in international science and technology cooperation, injecting fresh vitality into Shenzhen&#8217;s role on the global stage.</p>
<p>The future of biotechnology and healthcare looks promising as Shenzhen and Italy embark on this journey of collaboration. With their combined strengths and shared dedication to innovation, they are poised to make substantial contributions to the advancement of healthcare technologies, ultimately improving the well-being of individuals worldwide.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shenzhen Delegation Ignites Sparks of Innovation in Swiss Summit</title>
		<link>/archives/304</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 08:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://grosso.link/?p=304</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lausanne, Switzerland &#8211; September 25, 2023 &#8211; A delegation from Shenzhen, a Chinese city renowned for its technological innovation, arrived in Switzerland&#8217;s tech-savvy city of Lausanne yesterday for a groundbreaking trade and economic exchange. The forum, held at the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology in Lausanne (EPFL) Innovation Park, was graced by Wang Qiang, a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Lausanne, Switzerland &#8211; September 25, 2023</strong> &#8211; A delegation from Shenzhen, a Chinese city renowned for its technological innovation, arrived in Switzerland&#8217;s tech-savvy city of Lausanne yesterday for a groundbreaking trade and economic exchange. The forum, held at the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology in Lausanne (EPFL) Innovation Park, was graced by Wang Qiang, a standing member of the Shenzhen Municipal Committee.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-305" src="http://localhost/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/3fea4eb7-54fb-47be-91d8-e4517aebbacd_zsite.jpg" width="700" height="525" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/3fea4eb7-54fb-47be-91d8-e4517aebbacd_zsite.jpg 700w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/3fea4eb7-54fb-47be-91d8-e4517aebbacd_zsite-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" /></p>
<p><strong>A Meeting of Innovative Minds</strong></p>
<p>For the past 12 years, Switzerland has dominated global innovation indices, gaining recognition for its advances in modern industry and high-tech sectors. The convergence of these Swiss qualities with Shenzhen&#8217;s own reputation as a hub of technological ingenuity presents an intriguing possibility. What kind of synergistic magic could arise from this East-meets-West exchange?</p>
<p><strong>Connecting Business Landscapes</strong></p>
<p>According to sources from Shenzhen’s Overseas Chinese Affairs Office, promotional videos of Shenzhen and its Nanshan District were showcased during the event. Representatives from the city’s European Business Office outlined Shenzhen&#8217;s latest business environments and industrial features. The forum also included experts and scholars from Swiss engineering and scientific academies, who elaborated on the Swiss research and innovation ecosystem.</p>
<p><strong>A Focus on Mutual Investment</strong></p>
<p>The Shenzhen delegation engaged in project discussions with several Swiss early-stage tech companies, placing particular emphasis on investment environments and opportunities. Attendees lauded the superior infrastructure, formidable innovation capabilities, favorable business climates, and rich talent pools in both Shenzhen and the Greater Bay Area.</p>
<p><strong>Building on Years of Partnership</strong></p>
<p>The relationship between Shenzhen and Switzerland has grown increasingly close in recent years, yielding significant accomplishments. Switzerland’s expertise in sectors like trade, financial services, biomedicine, artificial intelligence, and precision manufacturing aligns well with Shenzhen&#8217;s own strategies to promote a symbiotic relationship between advanced manufacturing and modern service industries.</p>
<p><strong>Pre-Summit Visit to Biopole</strong></p>
<p>Before the trade and economic summit, the Shenzhen delegation toured Lausanne&#8217;s Biopole, Switzerland’s largest biomedicine incubator, laying the groundwork for future collaborations in the biopharma sector. Business representatives from both locations expressed their optimism for stronger cooperation going forward, citing the two cities&#8217; strategic locations, robust economic strengths, and leading internationalization standards.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-306" src="http://localhost/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/63dac6ff-f983-4f4c-aa69-c89be35af5e0_zsite.jpg" width="700" height="525" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/63dac6ff-f983-4f4c-aa69-c89be35af5e0_zsite.jpg 700w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/09/63dac6ff-f983-4f4c-aa69-c89be35af5e0_zsite-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In summary, the economic summit served as a fertile ground for cultivating a new chapter in Sino-Swiss relations, fostering a mutual commitment to win-win development and innovative leadership.</p>
<p><strong>Reporting by Chao, Grosso Link Sarl</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Electronica China 2023 : Une vitrine des électroniques de pointe et des innovations</title>
		<link>/archives/294</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 10:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://grosso.link/?p=294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shanghai, le 20 juillet 2023 &#8211; L&#8217;exposition Electronica China 2023, qui s&#8217;est tenue au Centre national d&#8217;exposition et de congrès de Shanghai du 11 au 13 juillet, a suscité un vif intérêt tant chez les entreprises électroniques nationales qu&#8217;internationales. En tant que plateforme de premier plan pour l&#8217;industrie électronique, l&#8217;événement a accueilli plus de 1 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shanghai, le 20 juillet 2023 &#8211; L&#8217;exposition Electronica China 2023, qui s&#8217;est tenue au Centre national d&#8217;exposition et de congrès de Shanghai du 11 au 13 juillet, a suscité un vif intérêt tant chez les entreprises électroniques nationales qu&#8217;internationales. En tant que plateforme de premier plan pour l&#8217;industrie électronique, l&#8217;événement a accueilli plus de 1 400 entreprises du monde entier, présentant leurs derniers produits et solutions dans divers domaines verticaux, tels que les semi-conducteurs, les systèmes embarqués, les capteurs, les microsystèmes électromécaniques (MEMS), les relais, les commutateurs et les connecteurs.</p>
<p>MPS (Monolithic Power Systems), un leader mondial dans le domaine des semi-conducteurs, et Sinomags, un fabricant chinois de capteurs magnétiques de premier plan, ont été parmi les grands faits saillants de l&#8217;événement, captivant les visiteurs avec leurs technologies de pointe et leurs innovations. MPS a présenté plus de 50 produits innovants destinés aux applications dans les secteurs de l&#8217;automobile, de l&#8217;industrie, de l&#8217;Internet des objets (IoT) et de l&#8217;électronique grand public. La stratégie de marché avant-gardiste de l&#8217;entreprise et ses capacités techniques ont été vivement saluées par les experts et les visiteurs.</p>
<p>Sinomags, quant à lui, a présenté sa technologie de capteurs magnétiques de pointe, consolidant ainsi sa position en tant qu&#8217;acteur majeur du marché. La large gamme de capteurs magnétiques haute précision de l&#8217;entreprise, notamment les capteurs de vitesse, les codeurs magnétiques et les capteurs de courant, a attiré l&#8217;attention de nombreux visiteurs. L&#8217;acquisition récente de Sensitec, un fabricant allemand de capteurs magnétiques, a renforcé davantage la position mondiale de Sinomags et a été saluée par les experts du secteur, qui y voient un avantage stratégique pour l&#8217;entreprise.</p>
<p>Alors que MPS et Sinomags ont été sous les feux de la rampe, d&#8217;autres entreprises notables ont également fait des présentations impressionnantes. Bourns, réputée pour ses inductances de puissance et ses composants électroniques, a dévoilé ses dernières inductances de puissance de qualité automobile conformes à la norme AEC-Q200. GigaDevice, une entreprise chinoise émergente et un leader mondial des fournisseurs de puces Fabless, a exposé son vaste portefeuille de produits de mémoire, de microcontrôleurs, de capteurs et de puces d&#8217;alimentation. Les offres de l&#8217;entreprise ciblaient des secteurs clés tels que l&#8217;automobile, l&#8217;industrie, l&#8217;IoT et l&#8217;électronique grand public.</p>
<p>Goldlysky, autre puissance nationale dans l&#8217;industrie de l&#8217;alimentation électrique, a présenté ses solutions d&#8217;alimentation complètes, axées sur des secteurs tels que l&#8217;industrie, la santé, l&#8217;énergie, l&#8217;électricité, le transport ferroviaire, les transports intelligents et les villes intelligentes. Les solutions d&#8217;alimentation complètes de Goldlysky ont été saluées pour leurs solides capacités de R&amp;D et leur potentiel à stimuler les avancées dans divers secteurs.</p>
<p>Qorvo et NI (National Instruments) ont également eu un impact significatif lors de l&#8217;Electronica China 2023. Qorvo a présenté ses technologies de connectivité et d&#8217;alimentation avancées, proposant des solutions innovantes pour les voitures intelligentes, les énergies vertes, les maisons intelligentes, l&#8217;Internet industriel des objets, et bien d&#8217;autres domaines. NI, une entreprise forte de plus de 40 ans d&#8217;expérience, a mis en évidence ses systèmes complets de test et de mesure, aidant les ingénieurs à relever des défis complexes dans divers secteurs.</p>
<p>Tout au long de l&#8217;exposition, les visiteurs en provenance d&#8217;Europe et d&#8217;Amérique du Nord ont exprimé leur admiration pour le niveau élevé d&#8217;innovation et d&#8217;excellence technique présenté par les entreprises chinoises telles que MPS et Sinomags. L&#8217;esprit de collaboration et l&#8217;envie d&#8217;explorer de nouvelles opportunités ont été soulignés comme étant les forces motrices des entreprises exposantes. Les experts et les analystes du secteur ont commenté que de telles expositions favorisent non seulement les avancées technologiques, mais aussi la coopération internationale, propulsant ainsi l&#8217;industrie électronique mondiale vers un avenir plus interconnecté et dynamique.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-296 " src="http://localhost/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/9662f5761bbe4d6581f85ac99403442cnoop-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="767" height="575" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/9662f5761bbe4d6581f85ac99403442cnoop-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/9662f5761bbe4d6581f85ac99403442cnoop-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/9662f5761bbe4d6581f85ac99403442cnoop-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/9662f5761bbe4d6581f85ac99403442cnoop.jpg 1080w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 767px) 100vw, 767px" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-295" src="http://localhost/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/22ceafb43a8947d9afd8493fdba11880noop.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="576" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/22ceafb43a8947d9afd8493fdba11880noop.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2023/07/22ceafb43a8947d9afd8493fdba11880noop-300x225.jpg 300w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cooperation and fair competition</title>
		<link>/archives/246</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 05:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://grosso.link/?p=246</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On April 20th, US Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen gave a speech at the Johns Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies in Washington on US-China economic relations. In her speech, Yellen stated that any efforts to decouple from China would be &#8220;disastrous,&#8221; and the US seeks to establish &#8220;constructive and fair&#8221; economic relations with China. However, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On April 20th, US Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen gave a speech at the Johns Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies in Washington on US-China economic relations. In her speech, Yellen stated that any efforts to decouple from China would be &#8220;disastrous,&#8221; and the US seeks to establish &#8220;constructive and fair&#8221; economic relations with China. However, the US will firmly defend national security even if it means sacrificing US-China relations. Yellen also criticized China&#8217;s support for state-owned and private enterprises, claiming that healthy economic competition can only be sustained under fair conditions.</p>
<p>The speech comes amidst rising tensions between the US and China, as the US government is preparing to take action against China in key areas while hoping to maintain broad trade and investment ties. China, in turn, has accused the US of using double standards and hegemonic logic, and has called on the US to stop interfering in China&#8217;s internal affairs and stop damaging China&#8217;s interests.</p>
<p>Overall, Yellen&#8217;s speech outlines the US government&#8217;s position on US-China economic relations, emphasizing the importance of cooperation and fair competition while also highlighting the US government&#8217;s commitment to national security. The speech is viewed by some as a gesture of goodwill, while others see it as a reflection of the ongoing tensions between the US and China.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Magneto-resistance sensors: a technology in full growth around the world</title>
		<link>/archives/222</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 11:17:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.qinpex.com/grossolink/?p=222</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Magneto-resistance sensors, such as anisotropic magneto-resistance (AMR) sensors and tunnel magneto-resistance (TMR) sensors, are devices that are sensitive to changes in magnetic fields and find applications in various fields such as automotive, biomedicine, robotics, and consumer electronics. The development of magneto-resistance sensor technology dates back to the 1980s with the discovery of giant magneto-resistance (GMR) [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Magneto-resistance sensors, such as anisotropic magneto-resistance (AMR) sensors and tunnel magneto-resistance (TMR) sensors, are devices that are sensitive to changes in magnetic fields and find applications in various fields such as automotive, biomedicine, robotics, and consumer electronics.</p>
<p>The development of magneto-resistance sensor technology dates back to the 1980s with the discovery of giant magneto-resistance (GMR) by Albert Fert and Peter Grünberg, who were awarded the Nobel Prize in Physics in 2007 for their work. Since then, this technology has undergone continuous improvements, leading to the development of more sensitive and high-performance AMR and TMR sensors.</p>
<p>The United States is a leader in magneto-resistance sensor technology, with companies such as Honeywell offering products such as the HMC1002 AMR sensor.</p>
<p>Germany is home to several leading companies in magneto-resistance sensor technology, including Sensitec, which specializes in high-precision magneto-resistance sensors. One of their flagship products is the CFS1000 current sensor.</p>
<p>Japan is also a major player in the development and production of magneto-resistance sensors, with companies such as TDK Corporation offering TMR sensors such as the TMR3101.</p>
<p>France is known for its innovations in TMR sensors, with companies such as Crocus Technology offering products such as the CT110 current sensor.</p>
<p>Switzerland is a leader in this field, with companies such as Sensirion specializing in high-precision magneto-resistance sensors. One of their flagship products is the SMR3180 current sensor.</p>
<p>China is a major player in magneto-resistance sensors, with companies such as Memsic producing AMR sensors for various applications. The company offers the MXD7203GL current sensor, among other products.</p>
<p>Magneto-resistance sensors work by detecting changes in the electrical resistance of a material when it is subjected to a magnetic field. AMR sensors exploit anisotropic magneto-resistance, while TMR sensors use tunnel magneto-resistance, a quantum phenomenon that occurs in thin-film structures composed of two ferromagnetic layers separated by an insulating layer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>La Chine accélère le développement de l&#8217;industrie des puces automobiles et envisage des collaborations avec des entreprises françaises</title>
		<link>/archives/212</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 10:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.qinpex.com/grossolink/?p=212</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Le Ministère de l&#8217;Industrie et des Technologies de l&#8217;Information de Chine (MIIT) a officiellement publié le projet de &#8220;Guide de construction du système de normes de puces automobiles nationales (édition 2023)&#8221; le 28 mars, sollicitant l&#8217;opinion du public. Le guide vise à développer au moins 30 normes clés de puces automobiles d&#8217;ici 2025 et au [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="reader-text-block__paragraph">Le Ministère de l&#8217;Industrie et des Technologies de l&#8217;Information de Chine (MIIT) a officiellement publié le projet de &#8220;Guide de construction du système de normes de puces automobiles nationales (édition 2023)&#8221; le 28 mars, sollicitant l&#8217;opinion du public. Le guide vise à développer au moins 30 normes clés de puces automobiles d&#8217;ici 2025 et au moins 70 d&#8217;ici 2030.</p>
<p class="reader-text-block__paragraph">Pour les véhicules à énergie nouvelle, le coût des puces automobiles est le deuxième plus élevé après les batteries électriques, ce qui en fait le deuxième composant clé le plus cher. Bien que l&#8217;industrie des batteries électriques de la Chine ait atteint une position de leader mondial, la route vers la substitution domestique dans le domaine des puces automobiles est encore longue.</p>
<p class="reader-text-block__paragraph">Les données actuelles montrent que le marché des puces automobiles est dominé par des acteurs majeurs tels que NVIDIA et Qualcomm, en particulier dans le segment des SoC de contrôle principal. La part de marché intérieure des MCU automobiles est d&#8217;environ 2%, tandis que les puces IGBT ont connu la progression la plus rapide en matière de substitution domestique, mais représentaient encore moins de 25% en 2021.</p>
<p class="reader-text-block__paragraph">La publication du guide marque une étape importante dans la quête de la Chine pour établir un système complet de normes pour les puces automobiles, ce qui est essentiel pour promouvoir le développement global de l&#8217;industrie. Les efforts continus du pays pour développer des technologies de puces nationales joueront un rôle crucial dans la réponse à la demande croissante de puces dans les véhicules à énergie nouvelle et intelligents.</p>
<p class="reader-text-block__paragraph">Des entreprises chinoises, telles que Huawei HiSilicon, font déjà des progrès dans le secteur des puces automobiles, démontrant le potentiel d&#8217;expansion du marché et de croissance compétitive. Par ailleurs, des entreprises françaises de renom telles que STMicroelectronics pourraient collaborer avec des partenaires chinois pour partager leur expertise et leurs ressources en matière de semi-conducteurs.</p>
<p class="reader-text-block__paragraph">Avec un solide soutien gouvernemental et des opportunités de marché favorables, ainsi que des collaborations internationales avec des entreprises françaises, l&#8217;industrie des puces automobiles en Chine devrait embrasser de meilleures perspectives de développement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
